#大家好 最近想吃螃蟹啦
Hi everyone! I'm craving for crabs recently.
#一直 一直都沒空來搞這個螃蟹
But I never, never had the time to catch some.
#今天剛好有空
It just happens that I can make it today.
#帶了兩個地籠
I took two traps with me
#我們來抓螃蟹 就在那下面
to catch the crabs. We just go down there.
#那下面很多螃蟹的哦
There're a lot of crabs.
#今年的拿藤果
Look! There are many,
#結了好多啊 你看
many wild melons this year.
#哇 這個香藤子
Wa! This is "xiang tengzi"
#你年長那麼多
It has so many fruits this year.
#你看 12345678
Look! One, two three, four, five ,six, seven eight
#十多串啊 (註︰村霸不是說「串」，但字幕是這樣顯示)
There is a dozen of bunches,
#上面還有
and even more up there.
#這邊下面也有
Here are also some below.
#裡面有幾個
There're several inside.
#你看
Look!
#這一個
This one,
#好大的啊
is really large.
#現在沒熟
But it's not yet ready.
#要過一二[SIC]個月才熟哦 那麼青 遇那麼小
It still needs a couple of month. It's still very green and small.
#我們放點 放了一點肉下去呀
We have put some, some meat into the trap.
#這個肉
Here is the meat.
#進裡面放
I'll put it inside the gorge.
#進裡面的還境比較好
The environment is better there.
#這裡一個水潭哦
Here's a pond.
#這水潭肯定
The pond must be,
#下面可能有
I think there are some.
#這個地籠就放好啦
I'll leave this trap here.
#這裡面有肉 等下螃蟹它會進去吃
There's some meat inside. The crabs will go inside to get the meat.
#走放下一個地籠
So the next trap.
#我把這個地籠放到這邊
I'll put this trap here.
#明天早上我們再過來看一下還有沒有
We'll come back tomorrow morning to see if there're any crabs.
#提了一個小桶過來
I took a small barrel with me.
#看能不能裝 裝很滿
Let's see if we can fill, fill it up.
#哇 有螃蟹哦
Wa! Crabs!
#我看到一個螃蟹啦
I can see a crab.
#哇 你看
Wa! Look!
#那麼多螃蟹
There're so many crabs.
#最少有十來隻哦
at least a dozen of them.
#只不過不大 很小
But they're all very small, not large.
#嗯 很多
Um! A lot!
#好多哇
Really a lot!
#下去 下去
Go down! Go down!
#都不下去
They're not going down.
#這塊肉都沒吃掉
They have not even eaten the meat.
#等一下螃蟹吃
Leave it to other crabs.
#哇 你看
Wa! Look!
#一下就搞了那麼多
These are from just one trap.
#還有一塊肉
There's one more piece of meat.
#丟給魚吃
Leave it to the fish,
#也是拿螃蟹吃
they feed on the crabs too.
#下面還有一個地籠
Down there is another trap.
#去看一下
Let's take a look
#你看 有哦
Look! There are crabs!
#不多
But not many,
#就幾隻
just a few.
#哎喲 這裡上面還有那麼多
Oyo! Why is it so much more up there?
#不只幾隻哦 也有七八隻
Not just a few, but almost ten.
#哇 搞了那麼多哇
Wa! There're so many.
#這肉給它們吃掉
I'll leave the meat for them.
#這些好小哇
These are very small.
#放掉一點 還那麼小一點點
I'm gonna release some. These are just tiny little crabs.
#都不夠我一口悶啦
It's not even enough for a single bite.
#你自由啦
You're free now.
#幸好今天的碰 今天的是碰到我
You're lucky that meet, that the one you met today is me.
#要碰 要是碰到兄弟的話你就麻煩啦
If meet, you won't be that lucky if you met my buddies.
#長左點啊
Grow up!
#下次我來網的時候
Next time when I come here,
#你們再來上釣
remember to come again.
#你們再來進那個網子裡面啊
Come to my trap again.
#好啦 今天的視頻就掉[SIC]這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#你看 就抓了那麼一丟丟
Look! We caught just a tiny little bit.
#桶又帶了那麼大的
Only the barrel is that large.
#現在回去啦
We're heading back now.